London, United Kingdom linkedin.com/in/ahmed-hamad-85b954103

### Ahmed Hamad

07568146700 <u>ahmed.hamad@outlook.com</u> <u>ahmedghamad (ahmed hamad)</u> <u>(github.com)</u>

Highly motivated software engineer – C, Python, Django, Flask HTML, HTTP, APIs, CSS, Bootstrap and SQL through a Software Engineering course and Harvard online CS50 course. Bachelor's degree holder in marketing and international business, hardworking professional that has worked in various industries for over 10 years before ultimately realizing my passion for logical thinking and problem solving.

Looking for a challenging role where my existing skills and qualifications can be used to the best of my ability, and where I can continue to further develop my skills and knowledge in the software development field. Able to work well both independently and as part of a productive team, work well under pressure and within a demanding environment where I am able to prioritize, demonstrating the motivation and problem-solving abilities required to meet demanding deadlines by managing my time efficiently while maintaining the highest of standards.

#### **Work Experience**

Lettings Manager Blue Square Residential Ltd May 2019 – Feb 2024
Lettings London, UK

- Making sure that our available stock has been communicated with other agencies.
- Drove voids down to minimum it has ever been.
- Building rapport with existing and new clients.
- Preparing all legal documents required for a new tenancy.

# Senior Sales Executive (Team Leader) SBT Co., Ltd. London, UK March 2017 - May 2018 London, UK

- Establishing a UK based sales Team (interviewing and hiring).
- Managing the sales team of 4 sales executives and make sure that they all hit their targets.
- Assisting the team in closing deals.
- Dealing with ad hoc problems and unforeseeable situations

Sales Executive SBT Co., Ltd. Jan 2016 – March 2017

London, UK

- Developing new markets.
- Building and maintaining relationships with customers and shipping lines.
- Achieving monthly targets of Achieving monthly targets of £ 20,000 30,000
- Generating new leads through email campaigns and cold calling.

## Master Card Travel Consultan Inspire Europe April 2014 – June 2015 Manchester, UK

- Working closely with website developers to customize it to MEA needs.
- Making sure all transaction went through on the payment gate for all 17 platforms and that confirmation, quotes have been sent to all the customers according to the SLA for the 17 platforms.
- Updating and creating the special offers on all 17 websites checking all the websites system settings and make sure that they are correct.
- Frequently testing for bugs and raising tickets on Redmine to the developers.

London, UK

• Ensuring that all clients are satisfied.

• Making sure that the news feed is sent to the clients on time and the quality is good before their bulletin.

#### **Business Development Executive** Carlson Wagonlit Travel

Jan 2012 - Jul 2012

Cairo, Egypt

Built a simpler company profile.

• Tailoring and delivering presentation for each client.

• Updating the CRM database.

• Identifying new clients for the pipeline.

#### **Technical Support Agent**

#### Sony VAIO link UK

Jul 2010 - Dec 2011

Cairo, Egypt Trouble shooting technical issues.

- Dealing with customer queries.
- Assisting Sony Vaio customers.

#### **Technologies and Languages**

Languages: Python and SQL

• Technologies: OOP, NLP, HTML, CSS, Django, GitHub, Git.

• Other: Data structures and algorithms.

#### **Education and Certifications**

• CS50 Introduction to Computer Science, Harvard.

Feb 2023 - Present

• Software Engineering bootcamp.

Nov 2022 - Feb 2023

• **B.Sc. Marketing and International Business,** Middlesex University.

2006 - 2011

#### **Projects**

• I have created over 40 programs in my portfolio the link can be found in the header.

#### Other

- Languages: Arabic fluent, English fluent.
- Riding motorbikes, football, working out, reading.

#### References

• References available upon request.